<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on George Hadjiyiannis</title>
    <link>https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on George Hadjiyiannis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making near-shoring and off-shoring effective.</title>
      <link>https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/blog/effective_nearshoring_offshoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/blog/effective_nearshoring_offshoring/</guid>
      <description>It seems that everywhere you look, companies are looking to create near-shore and off-shore partnerships, to increase their software development capacity and reduce costs. Interestingly, this is not limited to large companies; more and more SMEs are joining in. At the same time, we now have over a decade of experience with this topic in the industry, and have learned some hard-earned lessons. It seems not that long ago that companies were pulling back from off-shoring due to a significant number of challenges in making the partnerships effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the cost of software</title>
      <link>https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/blog/understanding_the_cost_of_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghadjiyiannis.github.io/blog/understanding_the_cost_of_software/</guid>
      <description>The standard cliché in our industry is that software projects always take twice as long, and cost twice as much. Of the two factors, however, it&amp;rsquo;s the financial one that does the most damage. Usually, timing does little damage in itself, other than making a company run out of money.
Without exaggeration, none of the companies I have worked with had a good understanding of how much a proposed software project would cost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>